Elijah Raffo

Portland, OR 97224

- (971) 275-7057
- eliraffo@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/eliraffo
- eliraffo.github.io

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

A business and data analyst with a passion for utilizing information to create and implement impactful solutions. Completed projects in optimization, database design, automation, machine learning, cost assessment, and improving functional areas. Has experienced working within a fast-paced environment, building a team, learning complex business systems, communicating nuanced concepts, problem solving, and being a self-starter.

EDUCATION

University of Oregon • Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

Major Concentration • Operations and Business Analytics

Minor

■ Computer Information Technology

Relevant Coursework: Supply Chain Operations and Management • Business Strategy and Planning • Predictive Analytics • Database Systems

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Analyst (Part-time)

Lane Forest Products, Inc. ● Eugene, OR

June 2018 - Current

Sept. 2015 - June 2019

GPA: 3.60 / 4.0

General Responsibilities:

<u>Performed</u> database queries, data analysis, and data visualization to answer varying stakeholder questions about business operations.

Reported weekly on material sent to an agricultural customer to inform managerial delivery schedule.

<u>Improved</u> multiple functional areas by redesigning spreadsheets thereby decreasing future spreadsheet maintenance and improving efficiency.

Worked with the Offsite Production Supervisor to redesign monthly reporting, contract generation, and offsite scheduling.

Operated as the inventory control specialist of a logistic reload which over 6 months which moved over 55,000 tons of material.

Partnered with the database manager to automate an extract, transform, and load process.

Operated as the export specialist for international orders by managing documentation, accounts payable/receivable, and movement of materials.

Created Project flowcharts and procedures to simplify and scale the international export of material.

Analytic Projects:

<u>Conducted</u> an analysis of the Delivery Department by quantitatively measuring costs and modeling possible profit/loss combinations which resulted in a proposed delivery pricing structure which is estimated to increase department annual profit by \$36,000:

- Created visual models for stakeholders which intuitively explained the profit margin of all order combinations (~50,000 combinations).
- Designed a spreadsheet which uses a Google Distance API to optimize the delivery price quoted to customers.

Supply Logistics Intern

Townshend's Tea Company ● Portland, OR

June 2017 - Sept. 2017

Implemented a redesigned Point-of-Sale interface at all Eugene Teahouse locations which resulted in:

Data that records Key Performance Indicators and can be used in a Material Resource Planning system.

SKILLS

Beginner

* R ● * VBA | Macros ● Demand Forecasting ● Regression Modeling ● Database Modeling ● React.js ● Google Analytics

Intermediate

* Excel ● * Tableau ● * Python ● SQL ● Optimization ● JavaScript ● MS Office | Visio, Access, Outlook

PROJECTS AND CERTIFICATES

Emerald Kalama Chemical Fragrance & Flavor Optimization • Project

Partnered with Kalama Chemical to build a model which is scalable, optimizes their product mix, and models varying production constraints.

Wine Classification ● Project

Using python, developed machine learning models like SVM, k-NN, and Forest Tree to classify the quality of a wine (up to an 85% accuracy).

Video Game Database • Project

Produced an ER diagram, a relational schema, queries, and database built to the second normal form to answer consumer questions.

Certificate of Outdoor Leadership ● 600 Hours of Training and Application

Over 3 years, developing leadership skills and survival skills in the backcountry. Applied these lessons as an assistant leader in university classes taught by the Outdoor Pursuits Program. Classes included leading groups of six on three-day backcountry outings in the snow and rain, completing a Wilderness First Responder Certificate, teaching outdoor rock-climbing safety, and teaching vertical rescue techniques.

^{*} Improved further outside of University by enrolling in online courses